NIZAR AHAMED S

Front-End Developer

https://snizarahamed.github.io/myportfolio

♣ +91 8870293646 mizarahamed.sheik@gmail.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I'm a front-end developer with two years of experience building high-performance, responsive Angular applications. I'm seeking new opportunities to expand my skill set and take on exciting challenges. My projects have consistently enhanced performance and boosted user satisfaction. I actively lead projects and introduce simple, effective technical improvements

SKILLS

AngularTypeScriptGitHub

HTML & CSS
 BootStrap
 Figma & Canva

JavaScriptBulmaMySQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

JAN 2024 - Present

vcidex solutions pvt ltd - Chennai

- Developed front-end architecture that improved scalability and performance of the website.
- Skilled in creating user interfaces, interactive prototypes, and design mockups using Figma.
- Proficient in using Canva for designing visually appealing graphics, social media content, and marketing materials with a focus on simplicity and creativity.
- Built a fully customized website from scratch without using online templates, resulting in a cost savings of over 25%

Front-End Developer (Angular, Beginner in C# and Database)

JUN 2023 - DEC 2023

vcidex solutions pvt ltd - Chennai

- Utilize Angular 15 to build a highly responsive and user-friendly application interface.
- As a beginner in C#, I will focus on establishing a connection between the front-end and back-end systems by creating and consuming RESTful APIs.
- Use MySQL to manage and store application data. I will write simple queries and learn how to effectively
 connect the MySQL database with the C# back end.
- Developed a highly responsive and user-friendly web application interface using Angular 15

PROJECT HANDLING

Business and Enterprise Solutions

- NBFC (Non-Banking Financial Company) Platform: Developed modules for employee onboarding and risk management to streamline operations.
- Finance, WOS, and HR Systems: Designed and developed features for Finance management, WhatsApp ordering, and HR modules.

Web Development Projects

 Developed and delivered websites for various domains, including company and product sites (VCIDEX), tours and travel, real estate, and Financial Services.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology 2017 - 2020

Jamal Mohamed College

Master of Science in Computer Science 2020 - 2022

Jamal Mohamed College

Responsive Web Design Certification 2024

Free Code Camp

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information provided in this resume is true and accurate to the best of my knowledge and belief.